NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files. 6174/011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- WAJ SRP Notes, 1988-1992 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Windham-Ashland-Jewett Central School Agreement between Board of Education and Teachers Association, July 1, 1988 to June 30, 1990; agreements with Noninstructional Staff Association, July 1, 1988 to June 30, 1991 and July 1, 1991 through June 30, 1994; NYSUT memo to field representatives re new Part 100 regulations for annual professional performance review, January 19, 1985; memo re grievance arbitration on behalf of several district employees; agenda for meeting of Parents and Taxpayers Organization, with attached president's opening statement, March 5, 1991; letter to school superintendent from State Education Department with recommendations for improving school lunch program, January 9, 1986; handwritten notes
- Windham-SRP, 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Handwritten letter from bus driver to NYSUT field rep Jan Vincent re difficulty obtaining family leave to care for sick mother, dissatisfaction with representation by local president, March 23, 1993; Agreement between Windham-Ashland-Jewett Central School District and the Windham-Ashland-Jewett Non-Instructional Staff Association, July 1, 1991 through June 30, 1994
- WAJNIS-Dismissal Grievance, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Letter of reprimand, letter of dismissal, and evaluation for custodian; denial of third-level grievance by Board of Education; performance appraisals, incident report, and letter of dismissal for custodian/bus driver; memo re vacation request; grievance, November 27, 1990
- WAJ NIS-Personal Leave Grievance, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Windham Non-Instructional Staff Association grievance form re approval of personal days; materials from American Arbitration Association re hearing
- WAJ N/S, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  Official reprimand for misconduct to bus driver for use of corporal punishment; Stipulation of Settlement between Windham-Ashland-Jewett Central School District and buss driver; Constitution for the Windham-Ashland-Jewett Central School Teachers' Association; Constitution and By-Laws for the Hunter-Tannersville Central School Teachers' Association
- WAJTA-Counsel, 1971-1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  District mission statement, middle school mission statement; letters of commendation to band instructor for spring concert; Greene County Music Educators' Association checklist of problems re effect of Regents Action Plan, June 5, 1986; memos from superintendent and principal re need for improvement of band, unacceptable job description, reduction in salary, attendance record, and demand for medical examination
- WAJTA-Reprimand, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Letter from principal to teacher re neglect of duty and violation of discipline code for using a squirt gun, June 6, 1989; letter from NYSUT field representative to Windham-Ashland-Jewett Teachers Association president re status of memo as reprimand or counseling letter, right to due process under 3020-a for tenured teacher
- WAJTA-Evaluation Procedure Demand, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Draft board policy re evaluation of instructional staff; document, Plan for the Evaluation of Instructional Staff; letter to schools superintendent from NYSUT field representative, requesting impact negotiations to avert grievance over unilateral change in working conditions. May 30, 1989; letter from labor attorneys Bond, Schoeneck and King, hired by district, indicating willingness to discuss procedure, June 5, 1989
- WAJTA-Part Time Service, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  Memorandum and Agreement; cover letter from NYSUT to president of teachers association; handwritten notes
- Windham-Teaching Certification, 1990-1993 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  Correspondence from State Education Department, attorneys, and others re certification question for special education teacher; copies of teaching certificates; classroom observations
- WAJ-Termination, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  Request for NYSUT legal review; correspondence re termination and offer of half-time position; copies of diploma, certification, application, letters of reference, letter of probationary appointment; handwritten notes
- WAJTA-Certification Extension, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  Correspondence re error by State Education Department in extending provisional certification for popular teacher following maternity leave, 3020-a charges by district; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes; ad by WAJ Parents and Taxpayers Organization criticizing Windham-Ashland-Jewett administration
- WAJTA-General Correspondence, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  Letter from NYSUT field representatives Fran Wolf and Harry Fairbanks to president of Windham-Ashland-Jewett Teachers Association re public relations materials; memo to faculty re negotiations presentation
- Windham-Ashland-Jewett TA Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  Letters from NYSUT field representative Harriet Sutherland to teachers association re highlights of contract settlement, March 26, 1985; request for members to lobby against tuition tax credit proposal (Marchi bill); general issues, 1984
- Windham-Ashland-Jewett TA Communications, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  Memorandum of Understanding, Teachers Contract 1978-1980; letter from NYSUT field representative Harry Fairbanks to president of teachers association, noting corrections needed before negotiated changes to agreement, February 2, 1984; letter from attorneys to tribunal administrator of American Arbitration Association requesting extension of time to file post-hearing briefs in salary case, May 7, 1984
- Windham-Ashland-Jewett, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  Memo re custodial staffing decision, with cover letter from schools superintendent to NYSUT field representative and article from Custodial Methods and Procedures Manual
- WAJ-SRP, 1985-1988 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  Salary schedule for cafeteria aides, driver/custodians, part-time drivers, clerk/typists, noninstructional custodians
- WAJ-Salary Agreement, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  Salary agreement; handwritten notes
- WAJTA, 1988-1993 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  Log sheets re services provided to Windham Teachers Association by NYSUT field representatives
- WAJ-SRP, 1988-1993 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  Log sheets re services provided to Windham School-Related Personnel by NYSUT field representatives
- WAJ-Resignation, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  Correspondence re abrupt resignation of chair of Committee for Special Education at Windham-Ashland-Jewett Central School, including letter from school superintendent to Commissioner of Education; letter from NYSUT labor relations specialist, advising teacher of her rights
- WAJTA-Evaluation, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  Letter from school superintendent to science teacher directing him to change teaching method, depending less on videotapes, noting classroom observations, complaints from parents; correspondence
- WAJTA-Instrumental Position, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  Letter to parents describing program; instrumental music program
- Windham TA-Tenure Question, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  9/87. Letters of reference; letter of probationary appointment; letter granting leave of absence to complete Master of Fine Arts degree; letter requesting extension of probationary appointment through leave of absence; minutes of board of education meeting, granting extension; copies of transcript and certification; classroom observations
- WAJTA-TA/Teacher Position, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  11/87. Letter to schools superintendent from NYSUT field representative indicating that teaching assistant was performing the duties of a certified teacher and therefore should be appointed to probationary status under Commissioner's Regulations for tenure; chronology of work assignments
- WCT (Wappingers Congress of Teachers)-Correspondence and Info., 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  Wappingers Congress of Teachers memo to district re retirement incentive; grievance forms; newsletters, WTC Commentator; materials re child abuse reporting procedures; letter from WCT president to principal of John Jay High School re threats by parent against teacher; letter from teacher describing incident; budgetary data sheet and comparison of tax rates; WCT position paper re proposed BOCES distance learning project; district policy re student attendance in high school; letter to NYSUT field representative from president of WCT re teacher injured by student and now on unpaid leave from injuries causing permanent disability, not earning service credit, December 13, 1990; correspondence between WCT president and NYSUT field rep re several teachers
- WCT-Early Retirement, 1988-1991 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  Correspondence re early retirement of guidance counselor, 1991; correspondence re medical leave and related issues, 1988-899
- WCT-Disciplinary Letter, 1989-1993 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  Settlement of 3020-a Charges at Wappingers Central School District; request for 3020-a hearing, with outline of charges; disciplinary letter
- WCT-Unemployment, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  Notice of denial of unemployment insurance payments and penalty to excessed teacher who did not disclose unavailability for work on days her children were sick; memo to excessed and temporary teachers from WCT president re litigation with district re unemployment insurance eligibility implications of substitute status, June 3, 1992
- WCT-Budgets, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  Advertisement in Poughkeepsie Journal by anti-tax group "REVOLT," with cover letter from WCT president Ron Warman to NYSUT field representative, August 12, 1991; newspaper clippings
- Distance Learning, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  Improper Practice Charge against Wappingers Central School District; Verified Answer by school district; decision of PERB assistant director; notice of Improper Practice Charge against Northeast, Arlington, Hyde Park, Wappingers, and Red Hook Central School Districts, October 23, 1992; Verified Answer by Arlington Central School District
- WCT-Inappropriate Placement, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  Correspondence between WCT president Ron Warman and NYSUT field representative re teacher's concern over inappropriate placement of student, potential child abuse; Commissioner's Regulations
- Kingston-Arb-ISS RM, 1984-1992 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  Collective Negotiations Agreement between the City School District of the City of Kingston, N.Y., and the Kingston Teachers Federation, affiliated with New York State United Teachers, the American Federation of Teachers, AFL-CIO, July 1, 1989 to June 30, 1992; Policy Handbook, Kingston City Schools, n.d.; description of Turn Around Program, 1984 and 1989; in-school suspension reports, 1985- 1991; handwritten notes re 1981-82 contract; grievance over failure to assign teacher aide to accompany teacher during in-school suspension supervision, October 3, 1991; response by district, denying grievance, November 27, 1991; Agreement to Settle Grievance, cancelling arbitration, May 1992
- Kingston-Medical Leave of Absence, 1985-1991 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  Letter requesting extension of medical leave of absence from Kingston City Schools; denial by superintendent, August 29, 1990; prior letters of approval; State Education Department section 3020-a Education Law Panel' s unanimous opinion and determination in the matter of City School District of the City of Kingston vs. Teacher; letter from teacheer's attorneys to Workers' Compensation Board, describing post-traumatic stress resulting from false accusations, January 2, 1991; related briefs and correspondence
- Kingston-Subs Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  Agreement between the Kingston City School District Consolidated and the Kingston Federation of Substitute Teachers of the Kingston City School District, July 1, 1992 to June 30, 1994 (draft 8/23/93); handwritten list of problems with draft, 8/27; memo to superintendent and letter to PERB advising of ratification
- Kingston-Federation of Substitutes, 1985-1991 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  Constitution of the Southern Adirondack Substitute Teacher Alliance, September 3, 1986; Memorandum of Agreement between Kingston City Schools Consolidated and Kingston Federation of Substitute Teachers, February 1991; newsletter of NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office, Mid-Hudson School Bell, April 1991, with list of local associations in VOTE-COPE campaign (ED 13); memo from Kingston Federation of Substitute Teachers to potential members of bargaining unit, noting start of negotiations, asking them to join, with attached survey re priorities, January 18, 1985; substitute teacher roster
- Kingston-Substitutes Memorandum of Agreement, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  Proposed by-laws, Kingston Federation of Substitute Teachers; original signed Memorandum of Agreement, copies, and related correspondence
- Kingston-Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  Constitution and By-Laws of the Educational Support Personnel; revised document, 2/24/93; letter signed by several members requesting a general membership meeting, October 22, 1992; related correspondence; grievance materials re holiday pay, discrimination in hiring; salary schedule; job descriptions; letter from NYSUT field rep Jan Vincent recommending ways to improve functioning of local
- Kingston-SRP Class Action Health Insurance, 1985-1988 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  Correspondence re grievance, demand for arbitration
- Kingston-ESP Correspondence-Civic Service Issues-Pardoti, 1985-1989 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  Signed agreement re change in working title of teacher aides to "education paraprofessionals," while retaining official title for purposes of Civil Service, with letter from attorney noting trend by teacher aides to change the name to disassociate it from the disease AIDS, November 29, 1989; letter from NYSUT field representative Linda Stanczik to Civil Service Department re attempted reclassification by Kingston school district for employee, failure to reach top three in open competitive exam, asserting that promotional exam should have been given instead, September 15, 1986; related correspondence; job descriptions for computer-related positions; letter from NYSUT field representative to local president, clarifying duties of teacher aides in various circumstances, April 3, 1985
- Kingston-ESP Drug Co-Pay Grievance, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Agreement between the Kingston City School District Consolidated and the Educational Support Personnel of the Kingston City School District, July 1, 1988 to June 30, 1991; grievance re health insurance prescription drug coverage, December 5, 1985; memo re sick leave bank
- Disciplinary Charges-KESP Section 75, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Stipulation of Settlement in the matter of disciplinary charges; statement of charges against Hazel Spano, April 21, 1988; letter from NYSUT field representative, urging teacher to take the settlement
- Kingston-ESP HMO Grievance, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Excerpt from agreement re health insurance coverage; resolutions by Kingston Board of Education re HMO participation; letter from Kingston Educational Support Personnel president to superintendent, demanding negotiations over change
- Kingston-Subs Contract, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Agreement between the Kingston City Schools Consolidated and the Kingston Federation of Substitute Teachers, July 1, 1985 to June 30, 1987; proposed by-laws, Kingston Federation of Substitute Teachers; meeting announcement, calling both union and non-union substitute teachers
- Saugerties-Tenure Denial, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, including reasons for tenure denial and response from teacher, request for leave of absence and approval; minutes of Board of Education meetings; classroom observations
- Saugerties-TA, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Collective Bargaining Agreement between the Board of Education of the Saugerties Central School District and the Saugerties Teachers Association, July 1, 1988-June 30, 1990; 1990 negotiations worksheets; salary schedules; extensive handwritten notes; classroom observation forms; Response to Recommendations to Deny Tenure
- Saugerties-SRP Bargaining Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Agreement by and Between the Saugerties Central School District and the Saugerties Federation of Employees, July 1, 1986 through June 30, 1988; draft proposals for a successor agreement, by Saugerties Federation of Employees; district proposals; handwritten notes re bargaining, September-October 1990; memo to membership re change in dues structure, September 26, 1990; response from NYSUT counsel Bernard Ashe to request for legal review for teacher, May 23, 1991; letter to teacher from Saugerties superintendent, informing teacherr that she had been excessed (fired) because of state funding cuts, March 6, 1991
- Saugerties-Incompetence, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Materials re 3020-a charges (incompetence based on lack of certification); Stipulation of Settlement; handwritten notes
- Saugerties-TA Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  PERB notifications of appointment of fact finder and mediator; salary schedule; newspaper clipping; handwritten notes
- Saugerties-Bargaining, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  Confidential negotiation proposals by Saugerties Teachers' Association, March 20, 1990; salary schedule; handwritten notes; newspaper clipping
- Saugerties-Conduct Unbecoming, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  Materials re 3020-a charges (conduct unbecoming and insubordination) against driver education instructor; agreement re release of information re alcoholism treatment program, maintenance of sobriety
- Saugerties-TA-EIT, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  Stipulation of Settlement between Saugerties school district and teachers association re distribution of Excellence in Teaching funds; handwritten notes
- Saugerties-TA EIT Grievance, 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  Question and answer sheet re Excellence in Teaching funds as it related to BOCES; salary schedules; grievance; Board of Education minutes; handwritten notes
- Saugerties-Cafeteria Worker, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  10/31. Grievance re cafeteria worker; agreement between district and Saugerties Federation of Employees; letter from district ordering cafeteria worker to submit to a medical examination
- Snow Day Grievance, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  Grievance re requirement that clerical workers work on unused snow days; agreement between district and employees federation; letter of agreement re snow days
- Saugerties-TA Personal Leave Grievance, 1983-1987 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  Document by Janet Clark, "Sequence of Events Relating to My Application for and Denial of a Personal Day"; personal leave request form and attached incident report re personal day revocation and docking; personal leave request and incident report re revocation; related grievance and correspondence; handwritten notes; printed agreement between Saugerties Central School District and Saugerties Teachers Association, July 1, 1984-June 30, 1986
- Saugerties-TA Contract, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  Memorandum of Agreement re early retirement program; salary schedules; confidential S.T.A. Negotiating Proposals 1988
- Saugerties-TA Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  1986-87 STA budget; salary schedules; correspondence on a variety of issues
- Saugerties-Termination of Employment, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  3/22/84. Grievance on behalf of terminated half-time special education teacher
- Saugerties-TA Contract, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  Printed booklet, Collective Bargaining Agreement between the Board of Education of the Saugerties Central School District and Saugerties Teachers Association, July 1, 1986-June 30, 1988
- Saugerties, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  By-Laws of Saugerties Federation of Employees; request from president of teachers federation to NYSUT president Tom Hobart to review constitution and by-laws to determine if it was in compliance with NYSUT policies, December 13, 1989; letter of resignation from Carle, January 7, 1990, with cover letter to remaining officers from NYSUT field representative; NYSUT model constitution for local affiliates; handwritten notes
- Saugerties-SRP Grievances, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  Agreement by and between the Saugerties Central School District and the Saugerties Federation of Employees, July 1, 1990 through June 30, 1992; draft memorandum of agreement; notification from schools superintendent re decision on grievances, April 23, 1993; text of grievances re teacher aides and cafeteria workers; 1990-92 hiring rates for school-related personnel; recall rights agreement
- Saugerties-SRP Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  Memos re Excellence in Teaching fund allocations; grievances re seniority for recall and promotion of cafeteria workers and teacher aides; handwritten notes
- Saugerties-Karla Wehr, 1987-1992 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  Classroom observation forms for substitute elementary teacher; response to observation of December 13, 1991; notification of tenure denial, January 14, 1992; response to recommendation to deny tenure (grievance), May 28, 1991
- Saugerties-Memorandum of Agreement, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  Salary schedules; draft memorandum of agreement; handwritten notes
- Saugerties Federation of Employees, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  Agreement, July 1, 1988 through June 30, 1990; Saugerties Federation of Employees Proposals for a Successor Agreement; District Proposals; draft Memorandum of Agreement; salary schedules; handwritten notes; letters from members commenting on changes they would like to see in next contract, including more flexible vacation window for clericals; minutes of meeting of federation, March 29; Highlights of New Agreement
- Saugerties Federation Settlement, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  Summary of settlement, with attached salary schedule, December 4; memorandum of agreement; agreement; related correspondence
- Saugerties-Memorandum of Agreement, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  Signed memorandum of agreement, with attached salary schedule
- Saugerties-FE Contract, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  Excellence in Teaching agreement; general agreements; salary schedule
- NPUT- Involuntary Transfers, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  Memo re transfer language in contract; handwritten notes
- NPUT-Verbal Abuse, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  Correspondence between New Paltz Central Schools district and New Paltz United Teachers re ongoing disciplinary problem (verbal abuse and physical intimidation) with math teacher; related memos; letters of complaint from parents; minutes of meetings, NPUT, and administration
- Liberty, 1983-1987 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  Liberty School Employees Association Building Representative Handbook; summary of agreement; job descriptions; cafeteria salaries; PERB notice of appointment of fact finder
- Red Hook FA-Tenure, 1972-1993 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  Letters from Red Hook Central School superintendent re tenure areas of appointment as elementary and special education teacher, transfers; legal memo re rights
- Red Hook Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 34)
  Draft form letter re requirement for employees granted leave to submit to a medical examination, noting refusal would be grounds for dismissal
- Tri Valley-SRP Organizing, 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  Correspondence between NYSUT labor relations specialist and chair of Tri-Valley Support Staff re affiliation with NYSUT, December 21, 1993-January 11, 1994; list of employees in various job categories; letter to attorney re arbitration panel for Wappingers Federation of Workers, March 1, 1994
- Tri Valley-Health and Safety, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 36)